WILLIAM DIFP

■ WillWebDesigns@gmail.com

www.williamdiep.me

4 (408) 605-1266

SF Bay Area, CA

in www.linkedin.com/in/wdiep

Full Stack Developer (Front End Focus) with a love of design who has seven years of experience in systems administration and tech support, and ten years of experience in teaching and mentoring. Recent positions include providing customercentric tier 1 and 2 support with scopes of project management and consulting services. Passion for teaching, building, and learning new technologies.

Skills

HTML5/CSS3

SASS

JavaScript/ES6

jQuery

Python

Templating Engines

Webpack

Gulp

Bootstrap 4

Foundation 6

Git

MVC Architecture

Content Management Systems

Responsive Web Design

Search Engine Optimization

Google Analytics

MailChimp

Adobe Photoshop

NodeJS

MongoDB

Digital Ocean

Amazon Web Services

Nginx

Apache

Education

San Jose State University

Bachelor of Science Health Science 2013 GPA 3.4/4.0

Foothill College

Associate of Science Computer Science 2018 GPA 3.85/4.0

Front End Developer Code Camp (Cañada College)

2016

Enrolled in a 16-week immersive training program learning front-end programming, data structures, algorithms, & agile development

Collaborated in agile teams to plan and create websites and web apps

Experience

theCoderSchool

Coding Instructor

San Jose & Fremont, CA · Jul 2017

• Instruct and mentor 6 - 16 year olds web development, game development, and data structures and algorithms using HTML5/ CSS3, JavaScript, and Python

Will's Web Designs

SF Bay Area, CA · May 2016 to Current

Full Stack Developer

- Design and full stack development of responsive websites and web apps, and database architecture for small businesses
- Consult with clients, provide scope of project, proposals, and statement of work

NASA Ames Research Center

Mountain View, CA · Jan 2013 to Jul 2013

Junior Web and Graphic designer (Intern)

- Generated, revised and, managed webpages for the Earth Science Division using HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript.
 Improving web accessibility while providing administrative support to senior team members
- Collaboratively worked in a team of 5 to effectively create over 25 high-quality designs of brochures, posters, and presentations using Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Photoshop in an aggressive one-month time-frame resulting an increase of \$28K funding
- Coached four interns on a 1-1 basis on using MS Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Visio and Adobe Photoshop increasing team efficiency by ten fold

GoFundMe

IT Administrator (Contract)

Redwood City, CA · Aug 2016 to Nov 2016

 Sole technician who provided technical support and systems administration to 100+ users in new office supporting executives, finance, marketing, and engineering departments

DominoComp Technology Source

San Jose, CA · Sep 2014 to Jan 2016

IT Support Specialist

- Provided tier 1 and 2 software and hardware support locally and remotely to 100+ clients
- Reduced help desk calls by 30% by developing end-user training and knowledge database

Citi's Sleepworld

IT & Customer Services Support

San Jose, CA · Jun 2011 to Sep 2014

- Provided desktop support and trained 25 staffs the efficiently use of business systems and peripherals improving weekly shipments by double
- Handled customer inquiries, billing concerns, service requests, and issued return merchandise authorizations

Foothill-De Anza Community College District

Cupertino, CA · Aug 2009 to Jun 2011

IT Support Assistant